Willem N. Elsdon

4 909-202-3855 ✓ willelsdon@gmail.com in linkedin.com/willem-elsdon • welsdon Poise, Idaho

SUMMARY: A highly motivated systems engineer with an active TS/SCI clearance and over three years of experience in mechanical design, systems engineering, and software quality assurance. I hope to join a rewarding and collarborative team where I can put my diverse set of skills to use in an exciting and industry leading company.

Professional Experience

Raytheon Intelligence & Space — Systems Engineer II

February 2022 - Present

- IV&T SEIT
- Lead daily Scrums via Jira with the IV&T team and brainstorm solutions to story blockers with leadership
- Create new feature files used in automation, leveraging Gherkin syntax and Visual Studio Code via VDIs
- Verify Discrepancy Reports (DR's) from creation to final integration, review pull requests using BitBucket
- Assist coordinating test plans and events for Integrated Master Schedule (IMS) milestones using Jira and Confluence
- Frequently travel to sites to help **integrate** the FORGE system, requires extensive cross-product collaboration Systems Engineering — SEIT
- Spearheaded an initiative to overhaul and polish the MBSE model of the FORGE system while adhering to SysML
- Worked with SMEs from all product teams to better structure and organize the model, ensuring a scalable and future proof representation of the system that adheres to **DoDAF** architecture
- Developed scripts (Apache VTL) for use with CAMEO that captures necessary information for customer facing documentation
- Led various customer meetings (Technical Exchange Meetings, TEMs), verifying requirements were met and appropriate actions were in place to meet the demands of those slated for completion

Raytheon Intelligence & Space — Systems Engineer I IV&T — SEIT

July2020 - February 2022

- Performed various tests (integration, regression, performance/SOAKs) throughout the system
- Wrote technical documentation (Test Cases, Integration Cases, Test Procedures) for new capabilities added to a legacy program, making sure to adhere to the requirements outlined in DOORS
- Participated in customer facing test events for requirement verification (ran, collected, and verified results)
- Brought new and updated documentation through review (review boards & critical review meetings)
- Troubleshot and documented all encountered issues using ClearQuest and root-cause analysis

Western Aircraft — Engineering Intern

October 2019 - April 2020

- Avionics Mechanical
- Utilized Solidworks to design tooling used in the repair and maintenance of private aircraft (Pilatus, Beechcraft, Dassault Falcon)
- Helped engineer solutions for the upgrade and repair of avionics, leveraging ANSI drawings that outlined installation and removal
- Communicated with FAA DER's to validate designs, once validated I worked with A&P mechanics throughout installation
- Took accurate physical measurements of aircraft internals to identify ideal mounting and repair locations
- Created drawings for maintenance tools of private aircraft, once the **BOM** was complete, sent out for quotes to local companies

Northrop Grumman — Composites Structure Design Intern

May 2019 - Aug 2019

- Ducts & Doors Mechanical
- Collaborated with managerial and engineering staff to determine optimal solutions (using CATIA) to repair composite parts damaged during the manufacturing process for the air inlet ducts of the F-35
- Communicated these repairs directly to Liaison Engineers where they were implemented immediately
- Officially revised three Material and Process (M&P) specifications to create a more efficient manufacturing procedure and presented these changes to a board of high-level engineers and managers
- Organized all previous repairs into one catalog, allowing for quicker repair acquisition and less manufacturing downtime

EDUCATION

Mechanical Engineering — Bachelor of Science

May 2020

Boise State University - Boise, Idaho

GPA: 3.7

Gem Scholarship Recipient, SWE Member, ME Club Treasurer, Concrete Canoe

Air Quality Lab — Research Assistant

- Organized, analyzed, and presented fine particulate matter data as an Undergraduate Research Assistant
- Utilized Excel, interpreted PM10 and PM2.5 data collected during the summer of 2017 within the Treasure Valley
- Analyzed causes of high PM2.5 concentration, causes of high PM10 concentration, solutions to minimizing the production of fine particulate matter, and what can be done as a short term solution
- Data was collected using state-of-the-art MOUDI II devices and the final report was presented to Boise State engineering faculty

Skills

• CameoEA, Solidworks, Linux, Atlassian, Excel, Scrum Master, Techincal Writing, Communication, VSC, SysML, Adaptable